### Contact

nlbhrptr@hotmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/nilabhrapatra-0092445a (LinkedIn) github.com/nilbro/ (Portfolio)

## Top Skills

Python
Data Engineering
Microsoft Azure

### Languages

Urdu (Full Professional)
German (Limited Working)
English (Full Professional)

### Certifications

German A2
Google Cloud Essentials
German Proficiency

# Nilabhra Patra

Data Engineering | Big Data | Industry 4.0 | IoT | Embedded Systems | Masters in Engineering@Fachhochschule Dortmund Stuttgart

# Summary

Open to and available for full-time job opportunities in the field of Data Engineering, Big Data, IoT and Embedded Systems from beginning of the year 2021.

Master Thesis-student at Robert Bosch GmbH in the field of Semantic Data Analysis in manufacturing environment.

International Masters student, currently at the last phase of the course Embedded Systems for Mechatronics at Fachhochschule Dortmund.

Experienced in Azure Data Services, Data Modeling, Data Cleaning, building Data Pipelines, Exploratory Data Analysis, Machine Learning and Deep Learning.

Open Source committer for the IoT project Eclipse Kuksa and Appstacle.

# Experience

Bosch

6 months

Thesis Student
July 2020 - Present (2 months)
Stuttgart Region

Semantic Data Analysis in Manufacturing Environment

Data Engineer March 2020 - June 2020 (4 months) Stuttgart Area, Germany

Grapes 5G Co-Founder September 2019 - Present (1 year) Germany

University of Applied Sciences and Arts Dortmund Wissenschaftliche Mitarbeiter April 2019 - December 2019 (9 months) Dortmund Area, Germany

Appstacle and Eclipse Kuksa

Infosys
Data Engineer
July 2016 - August 2018 (2 years 2 months)
Hyderabad Area, India

## Education

University of Applied Sciences and Arts Dortmund Master of Engineering - MEng, Embedded Systems for Mechatronics · (2018 - 2020)

St. Thomas' College of Engineering & Technology, Kolkata
Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Electrical, Electronics and Communications
Engineering · (2012 - 2016)

South Point High School, Kolkata (1997 - 2012)